<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>One minute</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>8</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>8</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Array of techniques to imprison a creature.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>See text (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>A binding spell creates a magical restraint to hold a creature. The target only gets an initial saving throw if its HD is equal to at least half your caster level.

You may have up to six assistants help you with the spell. For each assistant who casts suggestion, your caster level for this casting of the spell increases by +1. For each assistant who casts dominate animal, dominate person, or dominate monster, your effective level increases by a number equal to one-third that assistant's level (provided the target is appropriate for the spell). All the assistants must join in chanting the spell (see the details on the spell's verbal component, below). Your caster level determines whether the target gets an initial Will saving throw and how long the binding lasts. All binding durations are dismissible.

The binding spell has six versions. Choose one of the following versions when you cast the spell.

Chaining: The subject is confined by restraints that generate an antipathy spell affecting all creatures who approach the subject, except you. Duration is one year per caster level. The subject of this form of binding is confined to the spot it occupied when it received the spell.

Slumber: Brings a comatose sleep upon the subject for up to one year per caster level. The subject does not need to eat or drink while slumbering, nor does it age. This form of binding is more difficult to cast than chaining, making it slightly easier to resist. Reduce the spell's save DC by 1.

Bound Slumber: A combination of chaining and slumber that lasts for up to one month per caster level. Reduce save DC by 2.  Hedged Prison: The subject is transported to or otherwise brought within a confined area (such as a labyrinth) from which it cannot wander by any means. The spell is permanent. Reduce save DC by 3.

Metamorphosis: The subject assumes gaseous form, except for its head or face. It is held harmless in a jar or other container, which may be transparent (your choice). The creature remains aware of its surroundings and can speak, but cannot leave the container, attack, or use any of its powers or abilities. The binding is permanent. The subject does not need to breathe, eat, or drink while metamorphosed, nor does it age. Reduce save DC by 4.

Minimus Containment: The subject is shrunk to a height of 1 inch or even less and held within some gem or similar object or jar. The binding is permanent. The subject does not need to breathe, eat, or drink while contained, nor does it age. Reduce save DC by 4.

Regardless of the version of binding you cast, you can specify triggering conditions that end the spell and release the creature whenever they occur. These can be as simple or elaborate as you desire (but the DM must agree that the condition is reasonable and has a likelihood of coming to pass). The conditions can be based on a creature's name, identity, or alignment but otherwise must be based on observable actions or qualities. Intangibles such as level, class, HD, or hit points don't qualify. For example, a bound creature can be released when a lawful good creature approaches, but not when a paladin approaches. Once the spell is cast, its triggering conditions cannot be changed.

Setting a release condition increases the save DC (assuming a saving throw is allowed) by +2 and increases the cost of the spell's material components by one-half (see below).  

In the case of the first three versions of binding (those with limited durations), you may cast additional binding spells to prolong the effect (the durations overlap). If you do so, the target gets a saving throw at the end of the first spell's duration (even if your caster level was high enough to disallow an initial saving throw). If the creature succeeds at this save, all the binding spells it has received are broken.

Components: Specially made props suited to the specific type of binding (cost 500 gp), plus the spell requires gems worth at least 500 gp for each HD of the target.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Binding</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Enchantment</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Compulsion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Mind-Affecting</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
