<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 full round</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>Plant</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Your staff becomes a treant on command.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="focus"> 
   <string>The quarterstaff, which must be specially prepared. The
staff must be a sound limb cut from an ash, oak, or yew, then
cured, shaped, carved, and polished (a process taking 28 days).
You cannot adventure or engage in other strenuous activity during
the shaping and carving of the staff.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>You change a specially prepared quarterstaff into a Huge treantlike creature, about 24 feet tall. When you plant the end of the staff in the ground and speak a special command to conclude the casting of the spell, your staff turns into a creature who looks and fights just like a treant. The staff-treant defends you and obeys any spoken commands. However, it is by no means a true treant; it cannot converse with actual treants or control trees. If the staff-treant is reduced to 0 hit points or less, it crumbles to powder and the staff is destroyed.  Otherwise, the staff can be used as the focus for another casting of the spell. The staff-treant is always at full strength when created, despite any wounds it may have suffered the last time it appeared.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Changestaff</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
