<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>brd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>As lesser geas, plus it affects any creature.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>As lesser geas, except that geas/quest affects a creature of any HD and allows no saving throw.

Instead of suffering penalties to abilities, the subject takes 3d6 points of damage each day he does not attempt to follow the geas/quest. Additionally, each day he must make a Fortitude saving throw or sicken. A sickened creature moves at half his normal speed and suffers -4 penalties on both Strength and Dexterity. He heals damage at one-tenth his normal rate and cannot benefit from any magical healing effects. A sickened creature must make a Fortitude save each day or become crippled.  Once crippled, the subject is effectively disabled (as if he had 0 hit points) and can't choose to take strenuous actions.  These effects end 1 day after the creature attempts to resume the geas/quest.

Remove curse ends the geas/quest only if its caster level is at least two higher than your caster level. Break enchantment does not end the geas/quest, although limited wish, miracle, and wish do.

Wizard and bards usually refer to this spell as geas, while clerics call the same spell quest.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Geas Quest</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Enchantment</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Compulsion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Language-Dependent, Mind-Affecting</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
