<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>Magic</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Transfer spells to subject.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Until discharged</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>You transfer some of your currently prepared spells, and the ability to cast them, to another creature. Only a creature with an Intelligence score of at least 5 and a Wisdom score of at least 9 can receive this bestowal. Only cleric abjurations, divinations, or conjuration (healing) spells can be transferred.  The number and level of spells that the subject can be granted depends on her HD; even multiple castings of imbue with spell ability can't exceed this limit. If your limit of 4th-level spells decreases, and it drops below the current number of active imbue with spell ability spells, the more recently cast imbued spells are dispelled.

HD of         Spells
Recipient     Imbued
---------     ------------
1-2           One 1st-level spell
3-4           Up to two 1st-level spells
5+            Up to two 1st- and one 2nd-level spell

The transferred spell's variable characteristics (range, duration, area, etc.) function according to your level, not the level of the recipient.
Once you cast imbue with spell ability on another character, you cannot prepare a new 4th-level spell to replace it until the recipient uses the transferred spells or is slain. In the meantime, you remain responsible to your deity or your principles for the use to which the spell is put.
To cast a spell with a verbal component, the recipient must be able to speak. To cast a spell with a somatic component, she must have humanlike hands. To cast a spell with a material component or focus, she must have the materials or focus.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Imbue with Spell Ability</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates (harmless)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes (harmless)</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
