<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 full round</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Insect horde limits vision, inflicts damage, and weak  creatures flee.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Cloud of insects 180 ft. wide and up to 60 ft. high</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>A horde of creeping, hopping, and flying insects swarm in a thick cloud when you cast this spell. The insects limit vision to 10 feet, and spellcasting within the cloud is impossible.

Creatures inside the insect plague, regardless of Armor Class, sustain 1 point of damage at the end of each round they remain within, due to the bites and stings of the insects. Invisibility is no protection. All creatures with 2 or fewer HD are driven from the cloud at their fastest possible speed in a random direction and flee until they are at least 100 feet away from the insects. Creatures with 3 to 5 HD flee as well, though a Will save negates this effect. (This urge to flee is an extraordinary fear effect.)

Heavy smoke drives off insects within its bounds. Fire also drives insects away. For example, a wall of fire in a ring shape keeps a subsequently cast insect plague outside its confines, but a fireball spell simply clears insects from its blast area for 1 round. A single torch is ineffective against this vast horde of insects. Lightning, cold, and ice are likewise ineffective, while a strong wind (21+ mph) that covers the entire plague area disperses the insects and ends the spell.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Insect Plague</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Long (400 ft. + 40 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Summoning</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>see text</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
