<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Hides expensive chest on Ethereal Plane; you retrieve it at will.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>60 days or until discharged</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="focus"> 
   <string>The chest and its replica.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You hide a chest on the Ethereal Plane for up to 60 days and
can retrieve it at will. The chest can contain up to 1 cubic foot
of material per caster level (regardless of the chest's
actual size, which is about 3 feet by 2 feet by 2 feet). If any
living creatures are in the chest, there is a 75% chance that the
spell simply fails. Once the chest is hidden, you can retrieve it
by concentrating (a standard action), and it appears next to you.
The chest must be exceptionally well crafted and expensive,
constructed for you by master crafters. If made principally of
wood, it must be ebony, rosewood, sandalwood, teak, or the like,
and all of its corner fittings, nails, and hardware must be
platinum. If constructed of ivory, the metal fittings of the
chest must be gold. If the chest is fashioned from bronze,
copper, or silver, its fittings must be silver or electrum (a
valuable metal). The cost of such a chest is never less than
5,000 gp. Once it is constructed, you must make a tiny replica
(of the same materials and perfect in every detail), so that the
miniature of the chest appears to be a perfect copy. (The replica
costs 50 gp.) You can have but one pair of these chests at any
given time---even wishes do not allow exceptions. The chests
themselves are nonmagical and can be fitted with locks, wards,
and so on, just as any normal chest can be.
To hide the chest, you cast the spell while touching both the
chest and the replica. The chest vanishes into the Ethereal
Plane. You need the replica to recall the chest. After 60 days,
there is a cumulative chance of 5% per day that the chest is
irretrievably lost. If the miniature of the chest is lost or
destroyed, there is no way, not even with a wish spell, that the
large chest can be summoned back, although an extraplanar
expedition might be mounted to find it. 
Living things in the chest eat, sleep, and age normally; and
they die if they run out of food, air, water, or whatever they
need to survive.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Leomund's Secret Chest</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Summoning</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
