<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Traps outsider until it performs a task.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Instantaneous</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Casting this spell attempts a dangerous act: to lure a
creature from another plane to a specifically prepared trap,
which must lie within the spell's range. The called creature
is held in the trap until it agrees to perform one service in
return for its freedom.
To create the trap, you must use a magic circle spell, focused
inward. The type of creature to be bound must be known and
stated. If it has a specific, proper, or given name, this must be
used in casting the spell.
The target creature must attempt a Will saving throw. If the
saving throw succeeds, the creature resists the spell. If the
saving throw fails, the creature is immediately drawn to the trap
(spell resistance does not keep the creature from being called).
The creature can escape from the trap with a successful SR roll,
dimensional travel, or a successful Charisma check (DC 15 + 1/2
its level + its Charisma modifier). It can try each method once
per day. If it breaks loose, it can flee or attack you. A
dimensional anchor cast on the creature prevents its escape via
dimensional travel. You can also employ a calling diagram to make
the trap more secure.
If the creature does not break free of the trap, you can keep
it bound for as long as you dare. You can attempt to compel the
creature to perform a service by describing the service and
perhaps offering some sort of reward. You make a Charisma check
opposed by the creature's Charisma check. The DM then
assigns a bonus based on the service and reward, from 0 to +6.
This bonus applies to your Charisma check. If the creature wins
the opposed check, it refuses service. New offers, bribes, and
the like can be made or the old ones reoffered every 24 hours.
This can be repeated until the creature promises to serve, until
it breaks free, or until you decide to get rid of it by means of
some other spell. Impossible demands or unreasonable commands are
never agreed to. If you roll a 1 on the Charisma check, the
creature breaks free of the binding and can escape or attack you.
Once the requested service is completed, the creature need
only so inform you to be instantly sent back whence it came. The
creature might later seek revenge. If you assign some open-ended
task that the creature cannot complete though its own actions
(such as "Wait here" or "Defend this area against
attack"), the spell remains in effect for a maximum of 1 day
per caster level, and the creature gains an immediate chance to
break free. Note that a clever recipient can subvert some
instructions.
When you use a calling spell to call an air, chaotic, earth,
evil, fire, good, lawful, or water creature, it is a spell of
that type. For example, lesser planar binding is a water spell
when you cast it to call a water elemental.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Lesser Planar Binding</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels) (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Calling</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>see text</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
