<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>brd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Commands subject of 7 HD or less.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 day/level or until discharged (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
A lesser geas places a magical command on a creature to carry
out some service or to refrain from some action or course of
activity, as desired by you. The creature must have 7 or fewer HD
and be able to understand you. While a geas cannot compel a
creature to kill itself or perform acts that would result in
certain death, it can cause almost any other course of activity.
The geased creature must follow the given instructions until the
geas is completed, no matter how long it takes. If the
instructions involve some open-ended task that the recipient
cannot complete through his own actions (such as "Wait
here" or "Defend this area against attack"), the
spell remains in effect for a maximum of 1 day per caster level.
Note that a clever recipient can subvert some instructions. For
example, if you order the recipient to protect you from all harm,
it might place you in a nice, safe dungeon for the duration of
the spell.
If the subject is prevented from obeying the lesser geas for a
whole day, he suffers a -2 penalty on each ability score.
Each day, another -2 penalty accumulates, up to a total of
-8. Abilities are not reduced below 1. The ability penalties
end 1 day after the character resumes obeying the lesser geas.
A lesser geas (and all ability penalties) can be ended by
break enchantment, limited wish, remove curse, miracle, or wish.
Dispel magic does not affect a lesser geas.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Lesser Geas</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Enchantment</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Compulsion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Language-Dependent, Mind-Affecting</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
