<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Exchange services with an 8 HD outsider.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Instantaneous</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>One summoned elemental or outsider of up to 8 HD</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
By casting this spell, you request your deity to send you an
elemental or outsider (of up to 8 HD) of the deity's choice.
If you serve no particular deity, the spell is a general plea
answered by a creature sharing your philosophical alignment. If
you know an individual creature's name, you may request that
individual by speaking the name during the spell (though you
might get a different creature anyway).
You may ask the creature to perform one task for you, and the
creature may request some service in return. The more demanding
your request, the greater return favor the creature asks for.
This bargaining takes at least 1 round, so any actions by the
creature begin in the round after it arrives. If you agree to the
service, the creature performs the task you requested, reports
back to you afterward (if possible), and returns to its home
plane. You are honor bound to perform the return favor.
A creature may accept some form of payment, such as a magic
item, in return for its service. The creature may keep it or may
deliver the item to another member of your religion somewhere
else, where it can help the religion's cause.
Note: When you use a calling spell that calls an air, chaotic,
earth, evil, fire, good, lawful, or water creature, it is a spell
of that type. For example, lesser planar ally is a fire spell
when it calls a fire elemental.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Lesser Planar Ally</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels) (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Calling</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>see text</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
