<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Enables possession of another creature.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level or until you return to your body</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="focus"> 
   <string>Worth at least 100 gp.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
By casting magic jar, you place your own soul in a gem or
large crystal (known as the magic jar), leaving your body
lifeless. Then you can attempt to take control of a nearby body,
forcing its soul into the magic jar. You may move back to the jar
(returning the trapped soul to its body) and attempt to possess
another body. The spell ends when you send your soul back to your
own body (leaving the receptacle empty).
To cast the spell, the magic jar must be within spell range
and you must know where it is, though you do not need line of
sight or effect to it. When you transfer your soul upon casting,
your body is, as near as anyone can tell, dead.
While in the magic jar, you can sense and attack any life
force within 10 feet per caster level (on the same plane). You do
need line of effect from the jar to the creatures. You, however,
cannot determine the exact creature types or positions of these
creatures. In a group of life forces, you can sense a difference
of four or more HD and can determine whether a life force is
positive or negative energy. (Undead creatures are powered by
negative energy. Only sentient undead creatures have, or are,
souls.)
Attempting to possess a body is a full-round action. It is
blocked by protection from evil or a similar ward. You possess
the body and force the creature's soul into the magic jar
unless the subject succeeds at a Will save. Failure to take over
the host leaves your life force in the magic jar, and the target
automatically succeeds at further saving throws if you attempt to
possess its body again.
If successful, your life force occupies the host body, and the
host's life force is imprisoned in the magic jar. You keep
most mental abilities and gain some physical abilities, as with
polymorph other (except that you get the creature's actual
physical abilities, not average ones).
As a standard action, you can shift freely from a host to the
magic jar if within range, sending the trapped soul back to its
body. The spell ends when you shift from the jar to your own
body.
If the host body is slain, you return to the magic jar, if
within range, and the life force of the host departs (that is, it
is dead). If the host body is slain beyond the range of the
spell, both you and the host die. Any life force with nowhere to
go is treated as slain.
If the spell ends while you are in the magic jar, you return
to your body (or die if your body is out of range or destroyed).
If the spell ends while you are in a host, you return to your
body (or die, if it is out of range of your current position),
and the soul in the magic jar returns to its body (or dies if it
is out of range). Destroying the receptacle ends the spell, and
the spell can be dispelled at either the magic jar or the host.
Incorporeal creatures with the magic jar ability can use a
handy, nearby object (not just a gem or crystal) as the magic
jar.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Magic Jar</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Medium (100 ft.+10 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Necromancy</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
