<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>brd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Speaks once when triggered.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Permanent until discharged</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
This spell imbues the chosen object or creature with an
enchanted mouth that suddenly appears and speaks its message the
next time a specified event occurs. The message, which must be
twenty-five or fewer words long, can be in any language known by
you and can be delivered over a period of 10 minutes. The mouth
cannot speak verbal components, use command words, or activate
magical effects. It does, however, move according to the words
articulated. For instance, if it were placed upon a statue, the
mouth of the statue would actually move and appear to speak. Of
course, magic mouth can be placed upon a tree, rock, door, or any
other object or creature.
The spell functions when specific conditions are fulfilled
according to your command as set in the spell. Commands can be as
general or as detailed as desired, although only visual and
audible triggers can be used. Triggers react to what appears to
be the case. Disguises and illusions can fool them. Normal
darkness does not defeat a visual trigger, but magical darkness
or invisibility does. Silent movement or magical silence defeats
audible triggers. Audible triggers can be keyed to general types
of noises or to a specific noise or spoken word. Note that
actions can serve as triggers if they are visible or audible. A
magic mouth cannot distinguish invisible creatures, alignments,
level, HD, or class except by external garb.
The range limit of a trigger is 15 feet per caster level, so a
6th-level caster can command a magic mouth to respond to triggers
up to 90 feet away. Regardless of range, the mouth can respond
only to visible or audible triggers and actions in line of sight
or within hearing distance.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="materialComponents"> 
   <string>Worth 10 gp.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Magic Mouth</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates (object)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Illusion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes (object)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Glamer</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
