<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>You and your gear merge with stone.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>10 minutes/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Meld into stone enables you to meld your body and possessions
into a single block of stone. The stone must be large enough to
accommodate your body in all three dimensions. When the casting
is complete, you and not more than 100 pounds of nonliving gear
merge with the stone. If either condition is violated, the spell
fails and is wasted.
While in the stone, you remain in contact, however tenuous,
with the face of the stone through which you melded. You remain
aware of the passage of time and can cast spells on yourself
while hiding in the stone. Nothing that goes on outside the stone
can be seen, but you can still hear what happens around you.
Minor physical damage to the stone does not harm you, but its
partial destruction to the extent that you no longer fit within
it expels you and deals you 5d6 points of damage. The
stone's complete destruction expels you and slays you
instantly unless you succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 18).
At any time before the duration expires, you can step out of
the stone through the surface that you entered. If the
spell's duration runs out or the effect is dispelled before
you voluntarily exit the stone, you are violently expelled and
take 5d6 points of damage.
The following spells harm you if cast upon the stone that you
are occupying: Stone to flesh expels you and deals you 5d6 points
of damage. Stone shape deals you 3d6 points of damage but does
not expel you. Transmute rock to mud expels you and then slays
you instantly unless you succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 18), in
which case you are merely expelled. Finally, passwall expels you
without damage.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Meld into Stone</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Personal</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
