<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Deals 24d6 fire damage, plus bursts.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Instantaneous</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Meteor swarm is a very powerful and spectacular spell that is
similar to fireball in many aspects. When you cast it, either
four large spheres (2-foot-diameter) or eight small spheres
(1-foot-diameter) spring from your outstretched hand and streak
in a straight line to the spot you select. The meteor spheres
leave a fiery trail of sparks.
Any creature in the straight-line path of these spheres is
struck by each one and takes 24d6 points of fire damage (no
save).
If the spheres reach their destination, each bursts like a
fireball in a spread.
Each large sphere deals 6d6 points of fire damage. The four
spheres explode with their points of origin forming a diamond or
box pattern around the spell's central point of origin,
which you designate upon casting. Each large sphere has a
15-foot-radius spread, and each blast is 20 feet apart along the
sides of the pattern, creating overlapping areas of the
spell's effect and exposing the center to all four blasts.
The smaller spheres each have a 7 1/2-foot-radius spread, and
each deals 3d6 points of fire damage. They explode with their
points of origin forming a pattern around the spell's
central point of origin (which you designated upon casting) of a
box within a diamond or vice versa, with each of the outer sides
measuring 20 feet long. The center has four areas of overlapping
effect, and numerous peripheral areas have two or three
overlapping areas of the spell's effect.
Creatures caught in a blast can attempt Reflex saves for half
damage. Creatures struck by multiple blasts save against each
blast separately.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Meteor Swarm</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Long (400 ft. + 40 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None or Reflex half (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Fire</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
