<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>Luck</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>XP (see text)</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Requests a deity's intercession.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>You don't so much cast a miracle as request one. You state what you would like to have happen and request that your deity (or the power you pray to for spells) intercede. The DM then determines the particular effect of the miracle.  A miracle can do any of the following:

    *   Duplicate any cleric spell of up to 8th level (including spells to which you have access because of your domains).
    *   Duplicate any other spell of up to 7th level.  *   Undo the harmful effects of certain spells, such as feeblemind or insanity.
    *   Have any effect whose power level is in line with the above effects.

If the miracle has any of the above effects, casting it carries no experience point cost.

Alternatively, the cleric can make a very powerful request.  Casting such a miracle costs the cleric 5,000 XP because of the powerful divine energies involved. A request that is out of line with the deity's (or alignment's) nature is refused.

A duplicated spell allows saving throws and SR as normal (but save DCs are for a 9th-level spell). When a miracle duplicates a spell that has an XP cost, you must pay that cost. When a miracle spell duplicates a spell with a material component that costs more than 100 gp, you must provide that component.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Miracle</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
