<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>adp</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>brd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Creates decoy duplicates of you (1d4 +1/three levels, max 8).</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Several illusory duplicates of you pop into being, making it
difficult for enemies to know which target to attack. The
figments stay near you and disappear when struck.
Mirror image creates 1d4 images plus one image per three
caster levels (maximum eight images). These figments separate
from you and remain in a cluster, each within 5 feet of at least
one other figment or you. You can move into and through a mirror
image. When you and the mirror image separate, observers
can't use vision or hearing to tell which one is you and
which the image. The figments may also move through each other.
The figments mimic your actions, pretending to cast spells when
you cast a spell, drink potions when you drink a potion, levitate
when you levitate, and so on.
Enemies attempting to attack you or cast spells at you must
select from among indistinguishable targets. Generally, roll
randomly to see whether the selected target is real or a figment.
Any successful attack roll against a figment destroys it. A
figment's AC is 10 + size modifier + Dexterity modifier.
Figments seem to react normally to area spells (such as looking
like they're burned or dead after being struck by a
fireball).
While moving, you can merge with and split off from figments
so that enemies who have learned which image is real are again
confounded.
An attacker must be able to see the images to be fooled. If
you are invisible or an attacker shuts her eyes, the spell has no
effect, though being unable to see carries the same penalties as
being blinded: In addition to the obvious effects, a blinded
creature suffers a 50% miss chance in combat (all opponents have
full concealment), loses any Dexterity bonus to AC, grants a +2
bonus to attackers' attack rolls (they are effectively
invisible), moves at half speed, and suffers a -4 penalty on
most Strength- and Dexterity-based skills.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Mirror Image</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Personal (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Illusion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Figment</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
