<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Phantom dog can guard, attack.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/caster level or until discharged, then 1 round/caster level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Phantom watchdog</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You conjure up a phantom watchdog that is invisible to
everyone but yourself. It then guards the area where it was
conjured. The phantom watchdog immediately starts barking loudly
if any Small or larger creature approaches within 30 feet of it.
(Those already within 30 feet of the hound when it is conjured
may move about in the area, but if they leave and return, they
activate the barking.) The hound sees invisible and ethereal
creatures. It does not react to figments, but it does react to
shadow illusions. It is stationary.
If an intruder approaches to within 5 feet of the watchdog,
the dog stops barking and delivers a vicious bite (+10 attack
bonus, 2d6+3 points of damage) once per round. The dog also gets
the bonuses appropriate to an invisible creature. (For most
defenders, the invisible creature gets a +2 attack bonus and the
defender loses any Dexterity bonus to AC.) The dog is considered
ready to bite intruders, so it delivers its first bite on the
intruder's turn. Its bite is the equivalent of a +3 weapon
for purposes of damage reduction. The hound cannot be attacked,
but it can be dispelled.
The spell lasts for 1 hour per caster level, but once the
hound begins barking, it lasts only 1 round per caster level. If
you are ever more than 100 feet distant from the watchdog, the
spell ends.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Mordenkainen's Faithful Hound</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Creation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
