<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Door leads to extradimensional mansion.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>2 hours/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Extradimensional mansion, up to three 10-ft. cubes/level (S)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You conjure up an extradimensional dwelling that has a single
entrance on the plane from which the spell was cast. The entry
point looks like a faint shimmering in the air that is 4 feet
wide and 8 feet high. Only those you designate may enter the
mansion, and the portal is shut and made invisible behind you
when you enter. You may open it again from your own side at will.
Once observers have passed beyond the entrance, they are in a
magnificent foyer with numerous chambers beyond. The atmosphere
is clean, fresh, and warm.
You can create any floor plan you desire to the limit of the
spell's effect. The place is furnished and contains
sufficient foodstuffs to serve a nine-course banquet to a dozen
people per caster level. There is a staff of near-transparent
servants, liveried and obedient, to wait upon all who enter. The
servants function as unseen servant spells except that they are
visible and can go anywhere in the mansion. There are two such
servants for each caster level.
Since the place can be entered only through its special
portal, outside conditions do not affect the mansion, nor do
conditions inside it pass to the plane beyond. Rest and
relaxation within the place occurs as normal.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Mordenkainen's Magnificent Mansion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Creation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
