<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Floating magic blade strikes opponents.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 round/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>One sword</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="focus"> 
   <string>Worth at least 250 gp.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You bring into being a shimmering, swordlike plane of force.
The sword strikes at any opponent within its range, as you
desire, starting the round that you cast the spell. The sword
attacks its designated target once each round. Its attack bonus
is your level + your Intelligence bonus or your Charisma bonus
(for wizards and sorcerers, respectively) with a +3 enhancement
bonus. As a force effect, it can strike ethereal and incorporeal
creatures. It deals 4d6+3 points of damage, with a threat range
of 19-20 and a crit of x2.
The sword always strikes from your direction. It does not get
a flanking bonus or help a combatant get one. If the sword goes
beyond the spell range from you, if it goes out of your sight, or
if you are not directing it, the sword returns to you and hovers.
Each round after the first, you can use a standard action to
switch the sword to a new target. If you do not, the sword
continues to attack the previous round's target. The sword
cannot be attacked or harmed by physical attacks, but dispel
magic, disintegrate, a sphere of annihilation, or a rod of
cancellation affects it. The sword's AC against touch
attacks is 13.
If an attacked creature has SR, the resistance is checked the
first time Mordenkainen's sword strikes it. If the sword is
successfully resisted, the spell is dispelled. If not, the sword
has its normal full effect on that creature for the duration of
the spell.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Mordenkainen's Sword</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Force</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
