<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>F</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Freezes water or deals cold damage.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Otiluke's freezing sphere is a multipurpose spell. You
can cast any one of the following three versions:
Frigid Sphere: A tiny sphere of freezing matter steaks from
your fingertips to up to long range (400 feet + 40 feet/level) to
strike a body of water or a liquid that is principally water.
When it strikes such a target, it freezes the liquid to a depth
of 6 inches over an area equal to 100 square feet (a 10-foot
square) per caster level. This ice lasts for 1 round per caster
level. The sphere has no effect if it strikes a creature, even a
water-based creature, but creatures swimming on the surface of
frozen water become trapped in the ice. Attempting to break free
is a full-round action. A trapped creature must succeed at a
Strength check (DC 25) to do so.
Cold Ray: A ray of cold springs from your hand to close range
(25 feet + 5 feet/2 levels). You must succeed at a ranged touch
attack to hit your target. The ray instantaneously deals 1d6
points of cold damage per caster level (maximum 20d6).
Globe of Cold: You create a small globe about the size of a
sling stone, cool to the touch but not harmful. This globe is a
grenadelike weapon and can be hurled either as a thrown weapon
(range increment 20 feet) or in a sling. The globe bursts on
impact, dealing 6d6 points of cold damage instantaneously to all
targets within a 10-foot radius. Affected creatures can attempt
Reflex saves for half damage. If you do not hurl the globe, it
bursts on its own after 1 round per caster level. You can command
the globe to burst sooner if you wish, but the time cannot be
changed once set (though it still bursts on impact after being
hurled).
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Otiluke's Freezing Sphere</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Cold</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
