<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>8</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>8</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>As Otiluke's resilient sphere, but you move sphere telekinetically.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>1-ft.-diameter/level sphere, centered around creatures or objects</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>As Otiluke's resilient sphere, with the addition that the creatures or objects inside the globe are nearly weightless.

Anything contained within an Otiluke's telekinetic sphere weighs only one-sixteenth of its normal weight. You can telekinetically lift anything in the sphere that normally weighs up to 5,000 pounds. The range of the telekinetic control extends to a maximum distance of medium range from you (100 feet + 10 feet per caster level) after the sphere has succeeded in encapsulating its contents.

You move objects or creatures in the sphere that weigh up to a total of 5,000 pounds by concentrating on the sphere. You can begin moving a sphere the round after casting the spell. A round's concentration (a standard action) moves the sphere up to 30 feet. If you cease concentrating, the sphere does not move that round (if on a level surface) or descends at its falling rate (if aloft) until it reaches a level surface, the spell's duration ends, or you begin concentrating again. If you cease concentrating (voluntarily or due to failing a Concentration check), you can resume concentrating on your next turn or any later turn during the spell's duration.

Note that even if more than 5,000 pounds of weight is englobed, the perceived weight is only one-sixteenth of the actual weight, so the orb can be rolled without exceptional effort. The sphere falls at a rate of only 60 feet per round, which is not fast enough to cause damage to the contents of the sphere.

You can move the sphere telekinetically even if you are in it.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Otiluke's Telekinetic Sphere</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Reflex negates (object)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes (object)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Force</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
