<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>Travel</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>8</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Invisible passage through wood or stone.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>One usage/two levels</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Ethereal 5 ft. x 8 ft. opening, 1 ft./level deep</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>This spell creates an ethereal passage through wooden, plaster, or stone walls, but not other materials. The phase door is invisible and inaccessible to all creatures except you, and only you can use the passage. You disappear when you enter the phase door and appear when you exit. If you desire, you can take one other creature (Medium-size or smaller) through the door.

This counts as two uses of the door. The door does not allow light, sound, or spell effects through it, nor can you see through it without using it. Gems of true seeing and similar magic reveal the presence of a phase door but do not allow its use.

A phase door is subject to dispel magic. If anyone is within the passage when it is dispelled, he is harmlessly ejected just as if he were inside a passwall effect.

A phase door can be made permanent with a permanency spell.  You can allow other creatures to use the phase door by setting some triggering condition for the door. Such conditions can be as simple or elaborate as you desire. They can be based on a creature's name, identity, or alignment, but otherwise must be based on observable actions or qualities. Intangibles such as level, class, HD, and hit points don't qualify.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Phase Door</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Creation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
