<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>adp</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Gives one subject a new form.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Permanent</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Polymorph other changes the subject into another form of
creature. The new form can range in size from Diminutive to one
size larger than the subject's normal form. Upon changing,
the subject regains lost hit points as if having rested for a day
(though this healing does not restore temporary ability damage
and provide other benefits of resting for a day; and changing
back does not heal the creature further). If slain, the
polymorphed creature reverts to its original form, though it
remains dead.
The polymorphed creature acquires the physical and natural
abilities of the creature it has been polymorphed into while
retaining its own mind. Physical abilities include natural size
and Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution scores. Natural
abilities include armor, attack routines (claw, claw, and bite;
swoop and rake; and constriction; but not petrification, breath
weapons, energy drain, energy effects, etc.), and similar gross
physical qualities (presence or absence of wings, number of
extremities, etc.). Natural abilities also include mundane
movement capabilities, such as walking, swimming, and flight with
wings, but not magical flight and other magical forms of travel,
such as blink, dimension door, phase door, plane shift, teleport,
and teleport without error. Extremely high speeds for certain
creatures are the result of magical ability, so they are not
granted by this spell. Other nonmagical abilities (such as an
owl's low-light vision) are considered natural abilities and
are retained.
Any part of the body or piece of equipment that is separated
from the whole reverts to its original form.
The creature's new scores and faculties are average ones
for the race or species into which it has been transformed. You
cannot, for example, turn someone into a mighty weight lifter to
give the subject great Strength.
The subject retains its Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma
scores, level and class, hit points (despite any change in its
Constitution score), alignment, base attack bonus, and base
saves. (New Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution scores may
affect final attack and save bonuses.) The subject retains its
own type (for example, "humanoid"), extraordinary
abilities, spells, and spell-like abilities, but not its
supernatural abilities. The subject can cast spells for which it
has components. It needs a humanlike voice for verbal components
and humanlike hands for somatic components. The subject does not
gain the spell-like abilities of its new form. The subject does
not gain the supernatural abilities (such as breath weapons and
gaze attacks) or the extraordinary abilities of the new creature.
The new form can be disorienting. Any time the polymorphed
creature is in a stressful or demanding situation (such as
combat), the creature must succeed at a Will save (DC 19) or
suffer a -2 penalty on all attack rolls, saves, skill
checks, and ability checks until the situation passes. Creatures
who are polymorphed for a long time (years and years) grow
accustomed to their new form and can overcome some of these
drawbacks (DM's discretion).
When the polymorph occurs, the creature's equipment, if
any, transforms to match the new form. If the new form is a
creature who does not use equipment (aberration, animal, beast,
magical beast, construct, dragon, elemental, ooze, some
outsiders, plant, some undead creatures, some shapechangers, or
vermin), the equipment melds into the new form and becomes
nonfunctional. Material components and focuses melded in this way
cannot be used to cast spells. If the new form uses equipment
(fey, giant, humanoid, some outsiders, many shapechangers, many
undead creatures), the subject's equipment changes to match
the new form and retains its properties.
You can freely designate the new form's minor physical
qualities (such as hair color, hair texture, and skin color)
within the normal ranges for a creature of that type. The new
form's significant physical qualities (such as height,
weight, and gender) are also under your control, but must fall
within the norms for the new form's species. The subject can
be changed into a member of its own species or even into itself.
(If changed into itself, it does not suffer the abovementioned
penalties from the disorientation of a new form.)
The subject is effectively disguised as an average member of
the new form's race. If you use this spell to create a
disguise, you get a +10 bonus on your Disguise check.
Incorporeal or gaseous forms cannot be assumed, and
incorporeal or gaseous creatures are immune to being polymorphed.
A natural shapeshifter (a lycanthrope, doppelganger, experienced
druid, etc.) can take its natural form as a standard action.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Polymorph Other</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Medium (100 ft. + 10 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Fortitude negates</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
