<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 minute</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>1d4 floating eyes +1/level scout for you.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Creates 1d4 levitating eyes +1 eye/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You create ten or more semitangible, visible magical orbs
(called "eyes") that move out, scout around, and return
as you direct them when casting the spell. When an eye returns,
it relays what it has seen to you and then disappears. Each eye
is about the size of a small apple and can see 120 feet (normal
vision only) in all directions.
The spell conjures 1d4 eyes plus one eye per caster level.
While the individual eyes are quite fragile, they're small
and difficult to spot. Each eye is a Fine construct that has 1
hit point, has AC 18 (+8 bonus for its size), flies at a speed of
30 feet with perfect maneuverability, and a +16 skill modifier on
Hide checks. The eyes are subject to illusions, darkness, fog,
and any other factors that would affect your ability to receive
visual information about your surroundings. An eye traveling
through darkness must find its way by touch.
When you create the eyes, you specify instructions you want
the eyes to follow in a command of up to twenty-five words. Any
knowledge you possess is known by the eyes as well.
In order to report their findings, the eyes must return to
your hand. Each replays in your mind everything it has seen
during its existence. It takes an eye only 1 round to replay 1
hour of recorded images.
If an eye ever gets more than one mile distant from you, it
instantly ceases to exist. However, your link with the eye is
such that you won't know if the eye was destroyed because it
wandered out of range or because of some other event.
The eyes exist for up to 1 hour per caster level or until they
return to you. After relaying its findings, an eye disappears.
Dispel magic can destroy eyes. Roll separately for each eye
caught in an area dispel. Of course, if the eye is sent into
darkness, then it's very possible that it could hit a wall
or similar obstacle and destroy itself.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Prying Eyes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>One mile</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Divination</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
