<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>9</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Alters item to transport its possessor to you.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Permanent until discharged</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You create powerful magic in some specially prepared
object---a statuette, a jeweled rod, a gem, etc. This object
contains the power to instantaneously transport its possessor
across any distance within the same plane to your abode. Once the
item is transmuted, you must give it willingly to an individual
and at the same time inform him of a command word to be spoken
when the item is to be used. To make use of the item, the subject
speaks the command word at the same time that he rends or breaks
the item (a standard action). When this is done, the individual
and all that he is wearing and carrying (up to a maximum of 50
lb./level) are instantaneously transported to your abode. No
other creatures are affected (aside from a familiar that is
touching the subject).
You can alter the spell when casting it so that it transports
you to within 10 feet of the possessor of the item when it is
broken and the command word spoken. You will have a general idea
of the location and situation of the item possessor at the time
the refuge spell is discharged, but once deciding to alter the
spell in this fashion you have no choice whether or not to be
transported.
Material Component: Worth 1,500 gp.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Refuge</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Teleportation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
