<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>Plant</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>6</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Pushes away wooden objects.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
Waves of energy roll forth from you, moving in the direction
that you determine, causing all wooden objects in the path of the
spell to be pushed away from you to the limit of the range.
Wooden objects larger than 3 inches in diameter that are fixed
firmly are not affected, but loose objects (barrels, siege
towers, etc.) are. Objects 3 inches in diameter or smaller that
are fixed in place splinter and break, and the pieces move with
the wave of energy. Objects affected by the spell are repelled at
the rate of 40 feet per round. 
Objects such as wooden shields, spears, wooden weapon shafts
and hafts, and arrows and bolts are pushed back, dragging those
carrying them with them. (A creature being dragged by an item it
is carrying can let go. A creature being dragged by a shield can
unlimber it as a move-equivalent action.) If a spear is planted
(set) to prevent this forced movement, it splinters. Even magic
items with wooden sections are repelled, although an antimagic
field blocks the effects.
The waves of energy continue to sweep down the set path for
the spell's duration. After casting the spell, the path is
set, and you can then do other things or go elsewhere without
affecting the spell's power.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Repel Wood</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Medium (100 ft. + 10 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
