<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Up to eight creatures hide in extradimensional space.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
When this spell is cast upon a piece of rope from 5 to 30 feet
long, one end of the rope rises into the air until the whole rope
hangs perpendicular, as if affixed at the upper end. The upper
end is, in fact, fastened to an extradimensional space that is
outside the multiverse of extradimensional spaces
("planes"). You and up to seven others can climb up the
rope and disappear into this place of safety where no creature
can find you. Climbing the rope counts as climbing a knotted
rope, which requires a Climb check against DC 5. The rope can be
taken into the extradimensional space if fewer than eight persons
have climbed it; otherwise, it simply stays hanging in the air.
Pulling the rope free requires succeeding at a Strength check (DC
30).
Spells cannot be cast across the interdimensional interface,
nor can area effects cross it. Those in the extradimensional
space can see out of it as if a 3-foot-by-5-foot window were
centered on the rope. Anything inside the extradimensional space
drops out when the spell ends. The rope can be climbed by only
one person at a time. The rope trick spell enables climbers to
reach a normal place if they do not climb all the way to the
extradimensional space.
Note: Creating an extradimensional space within or taking an
extradimensional space into an existing extradimensional space is
hazardous.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Rope Trick</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
