<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Your touch corrodes iron and alloys.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>See text</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You corrode iron and iron alloys at a touch. Any iron or iron
alloy item you touch becomes instantaneously rusted, pitted, and
worthless, effectively destroyed. If the item is so large that it
cannot fit within a 3-foot radius (a large iron door or a wall of
iron), a 3-foot-radius volume of the metal is rusted and
destroyed. Magical metal items are immune to this spell.
You may employ rusting grasp in combat with a successful melee
touch attack. Rusting grasp used in this way instantaneously
destroys 1d6 points of Armor Class gained from metal armor (up to
the maximum amount of protection the armor offered) through
corrosion. For example, full plate armor (AC +8) could be reduced
to +7 or as low as +2 in protection, depending on the die roll.
Weapons in use by an opponent targeted by the spell are more
difficult to grasp. You must succeed at a melee touch attack
against the weapon. A metal weapon that is hit is instantaneously
destroyed. Note: Striking at an opponent's weapon provokes
an attack of opportunity. Also, you must touch the weapon and not
the other way around.
Against ferrous creatures, rusting grasp instantaneously deals
3d6 points of damage +1 per caster level (maximum +15) per
successful attack. The spell lasts for 1 round per level, and you
can make one melee touch attack per round.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Rusting Grasp</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
