<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>brd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Creates text symbol that immobilizes reader.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>Permanent or until discharged; until released or 1d4 days +1 day/level (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
When you cast sepia snake sigil, a small symbol appears in the
text of one written work such as a book, scroll, or map. When
this symbol is read, the sepia snake springs into being and
strikes at the nearest living creature (but does not attack you).
The target is entitled to a save to evade the snake's
strike. If it succeeds, the sepia snake dissipates in a flash of
brown light accompanied by a puff of dun-colored smoke and a loud
noise. If the target fails its save, it is engulfed in a
shimmering amber field of force and immobilized until released,
either at your command or when 1d4 days +1 day per caster level
have elapsed.
While trapped in the amber field of force, the subject does
not age, breathe, grow hungry, sleep, or regain spells. He is
preserved in a state of suspended animation, unaware of his
surroundings. He can be damaged by outside forces (and perhaps
even killed), since the field provides him with no protection
against physical injury. However, if he is reduced to -1 to
-9 hit points, he does not lose hit points or stabilize
until the spell ends.
The hidden sigil cannot be detected by normal observation, and
detect magic reveals only that the entire text is magical. A
dispel magic can remove the sigil. An erase spell destroys the
entire page of text. Sepia snake sigil can be cast in combination
with other spells that hide or garble text, such as secret page.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="materialComponents"> 
   <string>Worth at least 500 gp.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Sepia Snake Sigil</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Reflex negates</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Conjuration</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Creation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Force</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
