<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>7</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Step into shadow to travel rapidly.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
To use the shadow walk spell, you must be in an area of heavy
shadows. You and any creature you touch are then transported
along a coiling path of shadowstuff to the edge of the Material
Plane where it borders the Plane of Shadow. The effect is largely
illusory, but the path is quasi-real. You can take more than one
creature along with you (subject to your level limit), but all
must be touching each other.
In the region of shadow, you can move at a rate of up to seven
miles every 10 minutes, moving normally on the borders of the
Plane of Shadow but much more rapidly relative to the Material
Plane. Thus, a character can use this spell to travel rapidly by
stepping onto the Plane of Shadow, moving the desired distance,
and then stepping back onto the Material Plane. You know where
you will come out on the Material Plane.
Shadow walk can also be used to travel to other planes that
border on the Plane of Shadow, but this requires the potentially
perilous transit of the Plane of Shadow to arrive at a border
with another plane of reality. The transit of the Plane of Shadow
requires 1d4 hours.
Any creatures touched by you when shadow walk is cast also
make the transition to the borders of the Plane of Shadow. They
may opt to follow you, wander off through the plane, or stumble
back into the Material Plane (50% chance for either of the latter
results if they are lost or abandoned by you). Creatures
unwilling to accompany you into the Plane of Shadow receive a
Will saving throw, negating the effect if successful.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Shadow Walk</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Touch</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Illusion</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>Yes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="subSchool"> 
   <string>Shadow</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
