<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>10 minutes</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>clr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>3</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Corpse answers one question/two levels.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You grant the semblance of life and intellect to a corpse,
allowing it to answer several questions that you put to it. You
may ask up to one question per two caster levels. Unasked
questions are wasted if the duration expires. The corpse's
knowledge is limited to what the creature knew during life,
including the languages it spoke (if any). Answers are usually
brief, cryptic, or repetitive. If the creature's alignment
was different from yours, the corpse gets a Will save to resist
the spell as if it were alive.
If the corpse has been subject to speak with dead within the
past week, the new spell fails. You can cast this spell on a
corpse that has been deceased for any amount of time, but the
body must be mostly intact to be able to respond. A damaged
corpse may be able to give partial answers or partially correct
answers, but it must at least have a mouth in order to speak at
all.
This spell does not let you actually speak to the person
(whose soul has departed). It instead draws on the imprinted
knowledge stored in the corpse. The partially animated body
retains the imprint of the soul that once inhabited it, and thus
it can speak with all the knowledge that the creature had while
alive. The corpse, however, cannot learn new information. Indeed,
it can't even remember being questioned. 
Any corpse that has been turned into an undead creature
can't be spoken to with speak with dead.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Speak with Dead</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>10 ft.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>Will negates (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Necromancy</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Language-Dependent</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
