<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>2</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Creates disembodied glowing hand to deliver touch attacks.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>One spectral hand</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
A ghostly, glowing hand shaped from your life force
materializes and moves as you desire, allowing you to deliver
low-level, touch range spells at a distance. On casting the
spell, you lose 1d4 hit points that return when the spell ends
(even if it is dispelled), but not if the hand is destroyed. (The
hit points can be healed as normal.) For as long as the spell
lasts, any touch range spell that you cast of 4th level or lower
can be delivered by the spectral hand. The spell gives you a +2
bonus to your melee touch attack roll, and attacking with the
hand counts normally as an attack. The hand always strikes from
your direction. The hand can flank targets like a creature can.
If the hand goes beyond the spell range, goes out of your sight,
or if you are not directing it, the hand returns to you and
hovers.
The hand is incorporeal and thus cannot be harmed by normal
weapons. It has improved evasion (one-half damage on a failed
save against an area spell and no damage on a successful save),
your save bonuses, and an AC of at least 22. Your Intelligence
modifier applies to the hand's AC as if it were the
hand's Dexterity modifier. The hand has 1 to 4 hit points,
the same number that you lost in creating it.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Spectral Hand</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Medium (100 ft. + 10 ft./level)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Necromancy</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
