<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>drd</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>rgr</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>4</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>DF</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Step from one tree to another far away.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 hour/level or until expended (see text)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
You gain the ability to enter trees and move from inside one
tree to inside another tree. The first tree you enter and all
others you enter must be of the same type, must all be living,
and must have girth at least equal to yours. By moving into an
oak tree (for example), you instantly know the location of all
other oak trees within transport range (see below) and may choose
whether you want to pass into one or simply step back out of the
tree you moved into. You may choose to pass to any tree of the
appropriate kind within the transport range shown in the
following table:
Type of Tree        Range of Transport
------------        ------------------
Oak, ash, yew         3,000 feet
Elm, linden         2,000 feet
Other deciduous     1,500 feet
Any coniferous         1,000 feet
All other trees     500 feet
You may move into a tree up to one time per level (passing
from one tree to another counts only as moving into one tree).
The spell lasts until the duration is expended or you exit a
tree. Each transport is a full-round action.
You can, at your option, remain within a tree without
transporting yourself, though you are forced out when the spell
ends. If the tree in which you are concealed is chopped down or
burned, you are slain if you do not exit before the process is
complete.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Tree Stride</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Personal</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Transmutation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Teleportation</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
