<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<java version="1.4.0_01" class="java.beans.XMLDecoder"> 
 <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.magic.Spell"> 
  <void property="castingTime"> 
   <string>1 action</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="classes"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>sor</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <object class="burningbox.org.dsh.entities.ClassLevel"> 
     <void property="className"> 
      <string>wiz</string> 
     </void> 
     <void property="levelReached"> 
      <int>5</int> 
     </void> 
    </object> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="components"> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>V</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>S</string> 
   </void> 
   <void method="add"> 
    <string>M</string> 
   </void> 
  </void> 
  <void property="description"> 
   <string>Wall is immune to damage.</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="duration"> 
   <string>1 minute/level (D)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="effect"> 
   <string>Wall whose area is up to one 10-ft. square/level or a sphere or hemisphere with a radius of up to 1 ft./level</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="longDescription"> 
   <string>
A wall of force spell creates an invisible wall of force. The
wall of force cannot move, it is immune to damage of all kinds,
and it is totally unaffected by most spells, including dispel
magic. However, disintegrate immediately destroys it, as does a
rod of cancellation, a sphere of annihilation, and
Mordenkainen's disjunction. Spells and breath weapons cannot
pass through the wall in either direction, although dimension
door, teleport, and similar effects can bypass the barrier. It
blocks ethereal creatures as well as material creatures (though
ethereal creatures can usually get around the wall by floating
under or over it through material floors and ceilings). Gaze
attacks can operate through the wall of force.
The caster can form the wall into a flat, vertical plane whose
area is up to one 10-foot square per level, or into a sphere or
hemisphere with a radius of up to 1 foot per level.
The wall of force must be continuous and unbroken when formed.
If its surface is broken by any object or creature, the spell
fails.
</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="name"> 
   <string>Wall of Force</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="range"> 
   <string>Close (25 ft. + 5 ft./2 levels)</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="savingThrow"> 
   <string>None</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="school"> 
   <string>Evocation</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="spellResistance"> 
   <string>No</string> 
  </void> 
  <void property="type"> 
   <string>Force</string> 
  </void> 
 </object> 
</java> 
